Howie Hao Wang

About Me

A web designer and developer with a background in architecture.

My interest in tech started with work experience at WeWork. I was fascinated by how a data-driven approach is implemented in design. Later at SOM, I worked on an interior project involving VR. In my spare time, I self-taught programming and gradually realized my true passion for web development.

My diverse background prepares me with both design and develop skills:

A keen eye for design; professional experience using design tools; solve real-world problems by design thinking, research and analytical skills.

*1. watch a self-introduction video to get to know me.

*2. watch a portfolio presentation to better understand how I worked on my projects.

Education

University of Virginia

Aug. 2015 - Dec. 2017 | Charlottesville, $\vee\Delta$

Master of Architecture, GPA: 3.61, Scholarship Recipient GRE: 319 *Full score in Math.

University of Mining and Technology

Sep. 2010 - Jul. 2015 | Xuzhou, China Bachelor of Architecture, GPA: 3.89, Rank: 2/86, Full Scholarship Recipient

Certifications

Next.js & React: The Complete Guide Jan. 23, 2022

React: The Complete Guide Dec. 30, 2021

Node, Express, MongoDB Bootcamp Sep. 20, 2021

The Complete JavaScript Course 2021 Jul. 15, 2021

<u>Build Responsive Real-World Websites</u>

Sep. 8, 2021

<u>The Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp</u> Apr. 9, 2021 <u>howiewang2020@gmail.com</u>

(1) 434-227-8996

howiework.com

github.com/HowieWork

Projects

Snap App | MERN-stack web application

Share, navigation, architecture, plan. Snap App focuses on creating a photo sharing platform for people who love architecture. Inspired by real-life experience as an architectural designer. Read full story of Snap App.

Lunch Break | Built with Next.js & MongoDB

A blog site cares about work-life balance focusing on design, psychology and community. It derived from my own Wechat Official Account. The first article has reached 826 reads. Over 20,000 words have been published since launching. Read why and how I built Lunch Break.

React Guide | Built with React

I am currently working on my own guide for React including general components, patterns, interview questions.

Howiework | Built with React; Hosted by GitHub page

I completely redesign and rebuild my portfolio website using React. It is a major update from <u>previous design version</u> for my aspiring dev career.

Museum - NMAAHC | UI/UX design project

A mobile app design for a museum. Goal is to enhance visiting experience. Personal product project contains the whole process including UX research.

*Below is a list of tutorial projects. I am currently working on adding more features and customizing these projects. Stay tuned!

Natours | Built with Node, Express, MongoDB

A web app for helping people choose where to travel in North America.

Forkify | Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Search over 1,000,000 recipes. Find your favorite recipe and bookmark it.

Mapty | Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript

An app maps your workouts. Built with OOP, Geolocation API, Web Storage API.

Experience

Work

Freelance Designer / Developer

Mar. 2020 — present | Washington DC

Help clients rebranding; build portfolio sites with Wordpress/Squarespace. Worked on projects like Snap App, NMAAHC mobile app redesign.

Product Designer / Developer

Jul. 2019 — Mar. 2020 | Remote

Worked on MIAO product. Helped customer successfully rebrand their product, website using JS, HTML, CSS and integrate with their store-front design.

Architectural Professional at Skidmore, Owings & Merrill LLP (SOM)

Jun. 2018 — Jul. 2019 | Washington DC

Involved in an interior office HQ Project: work on SD, DD, CD; Worked closely with market team and clients. Integrated VR into presentation.

Architectural Intern at WeWork

Feb. 2018 — May 2018 | New York, NY

Worked closely with professions from tech background. Implemented data-driven design approach and research on space & profit efficiency.

Research & Volunteer

Moon Village Jan. — Jul. 2019 | New York, NY

SOM research project (collaborating with Europe Space Agency and MIT) Lumina Pavilion (UVa Bicentennial Celebration) Sep. 2017 — Oct. 2017

Skills

Programming languages

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python

Tools & Platforms

Git, MongoDB, Firebase, Vercel, Netlify, Heroku, Wordpress

Frameworks & Libraries

React, Next.js, Node.js, Express

Design

Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator)